SARA KEVORKIAN

FRONT FND DFVFI OPFR

■ sdkevorkian@amail.com • www.sarakevorkian.com • 253-332-7341 • Seattle, WA in sarakevorkian O sdkevorkian

SUMMARY

I am a Seattle-based front end developer that has delivered for a variety of industries including airlines and real estate. I am primarily a front end developer with some back end development experience. My background in biotech taught me the importance of flexibility and the mindset to break concepts down into testable pieces. I am an analytical thinker and love to ask questions, while keeping a collaborative, positive mindset. In my 2+ years of experience I have learned new technologies quickly to meet project needs.

EXPERIENCE

Consultant - Front End Developer, Seattle

AVANADE, Dec. 2018 - Current

June 2018 - Present

I was the lead FED on a team tasked to create a simpler and more intuitive version of a US airline's internal policy search tool.

Loversaw EED work between myself and an additional EED.

Responsible for all features, including search, a bookmarking system, saving notes, and gamification.

Guided development team toward a modular approach to saving policy data.

Directly collaborated with the client on UI decisions.

Took on additional back end work to move the project forward when blocked.

Used HTML5/Sass/JQuery/Coveo/Sitecore/C#/Gulp.

Sr Analyst - Front End Developer, Seattle

Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2018

As the lead front end developer, I integrated the newest version of Coveo search into an existing Angular/Sitecore intranet site.

Heavily customized Coveo search interface to create an engaging search experience.

Communicated directly with client team to clarify prototypes and requirements.

Identified Coveo component structure for the search page including components that could be used out of the box and that needed customization.

As I rolled off the project, guided a junior developer to finish remaining bugs within a set bucket of hours.

Used HTML/LESS/Coveo/AngularJS/Sitecore.

Aug 2017 - March 2018

I worked with the existing development team to solve UI bugs for a Coveo-driven Sitecore website.

I was extended as the sole Front End developer, and was responsible for performance enhancement, localization, and design change requests.

Improved performance of business critical property search page by 50-75% - reduced number of queries from 8 to 2 and page load speed from 10s to 5s. Implemented last minute feature request for a landing page carousel in one day.

Used HTML/CSS/SASS/JavaScript/JQuery/Coveo/Google Maps API.

Web Development Immersive, Seattle

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, Mar. 2017 - June 2017

Accelerated project oriented learning - 50+ hours per week over 3 months.

Practiced DRY coding and RESTful routing with CRUD operations.

Worked individually and as a team to develop full-stack web applications.

Kept a positive attitude while tackling challenging material.

Clinical Research Associate - Molecular Analysis / QC Lead, Seattle

HEMATOLOGICS INC., Nov. 2014 - Feb. 2017

Worked within an interdisciplinary team to coordinate clinical testing and prioritize STAT cases.

Developed technical protocols and managed version control.

Identified redundancies in the procedure manual and transferred the entire library of documents into Sharepoint.

Troubleshot issues in both the existing production pipeline and new materials.

Molecular Technologist II/Quality Assistant, Seattle

GENELEX CORPORATION, Sept. 2013 - Nov. 2014

Performed high throughput clinical DNA testing.

Managed purchasing and quality control Access databases.

Designed technical data organization and inventory tracking documents.

Implemented CAP quality control standards into procedure manual.

Molecular Technologist I, Seattle Molecular Technician. Seattle

Sept. 2012 - Sept. 2013

Sept. 2011 - Sept. 2012

SKILLS

TOOLS HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Angular.js, SQL, MongoDB, Web APIs, Git/Github, Bootstrap,

Materialize, Coveo, Sitecore, React, SASS, LESS, Gulp

ARTI ITTES Troubleshooting, Teamwork, Communication, Flexibility, Positivity, Organization, Self-Reliance

EDUCATION

VOLUNTEERING

GENERAL ASSEMBLY Web Development Immersive 2017

DOMESTIC VIOLENCE AND SEXUAL ASSAULT SERVICES OF WHATCOM COUNTY -Communicated effectively and compassionately with individuals in high stress situations